Hi, in this lesson, I will show you some video examples of custom instructions for GitHub
Copilot.
There is a nice project on GitHub, which calls other song Copilot, and here you can find
different, uh, that most collections and instructions from the script, so you can over
you read about it, and they will look at these lessons, especially at the instructions.
So, uh, this is kind of community workspace where you can find a lot of instruction examples
for different languages and domains, so, and they will go through some front-end instructions
one by one, and they will show you how it's built and how it's written.
Okay, when you open an instructions folder, you can see inside bar a lot of instructions,
and I already opened some related to the front-end.
I want to show you.
Now, the testing structure is a React JS development instructions, so, um, you can view
it in preview format, and, of course, you can switch to the code, and you will see the mark
down file, this is exactly how you need to copy paste it to your, the custom instructions
file.
Hmm.
Okay, let's switch to the preview one, uh, so, this instruction is for just a visual documentation,
you have different sections, you have your project context that this is related to React,
the script, uh, we use functional components, and this hooks as default, we follow React
official style guide, et cetera, we use modern build tools, like with create React app and
custom web parks, a top, top, now you see the development standards, this is how AI should
develop follows this instruction, so, uh, we have architecture section where we say clearly
the sound commands that AI should use functional components with hooks, it should implement
components composition over inheritance, now it should organize component by feature or the
main orders of scalability and et cetera, we see here is a TypeScript integration, some
define some rules for TypeScript, that it should use trick mode in test config file, it
should use TypeScript interfaces for props, it should define proper types for event handlers,
et cetera, so we see some component design, yeah, about some responsibility principles,
some best practices for the art, we have also state management section, uh, this is how
like you should use hooks, yeah, and now we have hooks and effect, action styling, so there
is a lot of sections about data fetching about raw handling, as this config is really general,
uh, it's kind of okay, um, there are sections like HTML, security styling, the React code
and et cetera, hooks, so just use the best practices, uh, follow official documentation,
use latest on bars and et cetera, so there's a something you can start with, uh, for example,
the next one is more precise, there is a 10 stack library for fetching, um, API queries
on a client and caching them, also it uses shots and UI library, uh, for developing components,
and you can find here are more strict rules, like first we define the technical stack, uh,
what libraries, uh, mentioned in this, uh, instruction, then you have the code style rules
that never use type use proper type script types, et cetera, and you have what is nice,
you have an examples right here, how you should define the components. For example,
this is a example, how we should define the basic component, you should provide an interface
with a type script, and you should provide the functional component with props, and for example,
bottom, yep. Then you have a data fetching section, so you have some sub sections, yep,
how to use, uh, what use rect query, uh, it's the same as stun stack, you have a clear example,
like how we should define your API call, how we should then use your API call, like you have
also separate section with validation, like how we should, what schema, like you should define for
your, um, data model, yep. This is fine because I like the code examples, so if you have project
where you have some strict, uh, standards, you can create some basic examples and also provide it
in the custom instructions, so you have your follow it. Normally it should look at the siblings
folders, uh, and try to follow this style, but of course, much better and more chance to get
result as you expect if you define your own code examples. So this is why I like this custom
instructions. So the next one is for next jazz project, which is over you and it that you will
have an overview of what is possible, what you can put in the custom instructions. For example,
you can combine them, you can choose, for example, some code examples from this instruction
and some basic rules from this instruction solved. Um, let's look now at the, at the next
jazz best practices. So you hear it defines the clear is the project structure. So how you'd
like to start your application, then you describe some rules, yep, some of the creating files,
then you describe the k, uh, how to describe the client and server components,
how exactly AI should name it and what structure they should have. There are also some component
best practices, like there is a naming conventions, like we use the Pascal case naming for
component files. We use camel case for naming the hooks and snake case, okay, Bob case or some static
assets. So if you like them, you can use, uh, but it's really nice to define your own naming
conventions in custom instructions, how you name the files, folders, how you name variables,
constants, environment variables, how you name methods, how you name handlers, if you have
prefix handle or not. So this is all useful in the eye, you'll write quote more, uh, following your
expectations. So, okay, you can look at, uh, into your own. Uh, let's switch to the next one. This
is a config customer instruction from next jazz and tile wind. So you can see that there is a just
least of instructions that you just use responsive design patterns, dark mode support, etc.
Oh, this is kind of a simple instruction. And what's it like? The implementation process,
it feels the eye should plan component. Here are his and defined types, some implements,
server logic, build components, etc. So this is really nice, uh, pattern to follow in your custom
instructions. If you'd like a I do it step by step, and, uh, you can always verify it. You can
also ask a guy like do it with create a plan, uh, and show an examples, how you apply, how he
see to build it and you can verify it. And then you can, if you like it, you can build, if more,
you can update the plan. So, uh, the next one is TypeScript development, custom instructions,
you see it also has some general rules. So you can also see what you like from it and choose
something. Yeah, like we have the new section for formatting and style, or we can just run the command
to always be sure we follow the styles. I like, uh, for us in cronies code, we use us incubate,
we wrap everything to try cash, we structured error messages. So it's also important. So we can
copy paste it from it. Uh, it's good rules. And next one is, uh, GitHub, uh, issue planner, uh,
I see it. I have more one for TypeScript. You can also use search here. Uh, okay, we have instructions,
yeah, only one instruction for TypeScript, uh, collections. Okay, let's look at one more. Like,
if you write unit tests, uh, using, or integration tests using playwright, uh, playwright, yeah,
uh, you can also check these instructions. Uh, here, you provide the example of the test structures,
um, doesn't matter. Use this to use jazz to be test. So you can provide an example of how
you'd like to write unit tests. So AI will follow the structure. This is, it's already fine. If you
will switch to code, you'll see how it's formatted. And we just add a code block right here,
and just provides a block of code. And for example, um, okay, also we have some checklist,
yeah. Uh, before finalizing test, ensure you check this, this and this, yeah, you also can add
some checklist into custom instructions. Maybe just to wrap up, um, I recommend you look, uh,
different instructions right here. And define just something you can start. You shouldn't build an
ideal instruction, uh, at the beginning, because you will never build it. Yeah. Um, you need to build
something simple in all these five scenarios, just play with it, see how it works for you.
If you like it and then when you face with some situations, you can extend it step by step,
roll by roll. And this is the best way how to build your personal instructions.